A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Interview Transcripts and Subject Files, undated; 1; 12 Cubic Feet
  - Interview People (Box 10, Folder 389)
  - Hecksher Interview (Box 10, Folder 390)
  - Vice Presidency, 5 folders (Box 10, Folder 391-395)
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  This series consists of audiotaped interviews conducted by author Cary Reich for the first volume, and anticipated second volume, of "The Life of Nelson A. Rockefeller." Additionally, there are partial audiotaped interviews for Reich's "New York Times" expose "The Creative Mind: The Innovator," from April 21, 1985, as well as for other financial articles by Reich.
  Lastly, the series contains audio interviews conducted by Patricia Linden for a "Town and Country" magazine article ("Rockefellers' Monumental Legacy," September 1982) that highlights the Rockefeller legacy in New York. She was also working on her own unrealized, unauthorized biography of Nelson Rockefeller.
  Sound recordings
  - A-B, 2.1
    - Abramovitz, Max, 1982 September 28; 1/4 audio cassette (Tape AV 9446)
      Access copy available.
      Interview. Abramovitz was an architect and business partner of Wallace Harrison. Interview with Abramovitz ends at 93 minutes, 52 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with two unidentified individuals until tape ends at 233 minutes.
    - Abrams, Al, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9447)
      Interview. Abrams worked on Nelson Rockefeller's campaigns for the Republican presidential nomination in 1964 and 1968.
    - Adams, Sherman, 1982 September 21-22; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9448)
      Interview. Adams was White House Chief of Staff during President Dwight D. Eisenhower's administration. He had previously served as Governor of New Hampshire. Adams interview ends at 242 minutes, 39 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with woman identified as Mary Lou until end.
    - Albright, Harry - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9449)
      Interview. Albright was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller, 1967-1975. During Rockefeller's governorship, Albright held various positions, including deputy secretary, executive secretary, and appointments officer. He was also state banking superintendent, 1972-1974. He then served has Rockefeller's special counsel when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Albright, Harry - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9450)
    - Alcorn, Meade, 1982 October 4; October 27 1982; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9451)
      Interview. Alcorn was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller and Republican National Chairman.
    - Aldrich, Alexander (Sam), 1982 November 15; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9452)
      Interview. Aldrich was a cousin of Nelson Rockefeller who served as a gubernatorial advisor.
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Loud buzz and low volume throughout tape. Pitch is too fast.
    - Aldrich, Richard - Part 1, 1982 November 16; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9453)
      Interview. Aldrich was a cousin and IBEC aide.
    - Aldrich, Richard - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes (Tape AV 9487)
      Interview. Aldrich was a cousin and IBEC aide. Aldrich interview ends at 57 minutes, 30 seconds. Tape then contains partial interviews with two unidentified individuals until end.
    - Aldrich, Sam, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9454)
      Interview. Aldrich was a cousin and Governor Rockefeller's special assistant on race relations.
    - Anderson, Warren, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9455)
      Interview. Anderson was a New York State Senator.
    - Andre, James, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9456)
      Interview. Andre was a New York State Republican committee chair and then Clinton County Republican chair. He previously was a state trooper and worked security at the State House in Albany. Andre interview ends at 86 minutes, 26 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Paul Volker until end. Volcker was an economist for the Federal Reserve Bank of New York (1952-1957) and then at Chase Manhattan Bank (1957-1962). He was later Chair of the U.S. Federal Reserve from 1979 to 1987.
    - Armao, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9457)
      Interview. Armao was a labor relations aide. Armao interview ends at 71 minutes, 14 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Dan Mahoney until end. Mahoney helped found the New York Conservative Party in 1962.
    - Arndt, Willis, 1984 October 4; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9458)
      Interview. Arndt was an IBEC aide. No aduio for the first 30 minutes, 17 seconds.
    - Aurelio, Richard, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9459)
      Interview. Aurelio was a journalist and campaign manager for New York City Mayor John Lindsay in 1969. Aurelio interview ends at 143 minutes, 36 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified Beth Moore until end. Moore was chairman of the board of the State University of New York and friend of Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Bagley, Harry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9460)
      Interview. Bagley was an AIA-IBEC aide.
    - Barclay, Douglas, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9461)
      Interview. Barclay was a New York State senator.
    - Barnes, Janet, 1972; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9462)
      Interview. Interview ends at 30 minutes, 15 seconds. Remainder of tape is blank.
      Sound is extremely muffled and sometimes unintelligible.
    - Beichman, Arnold, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9463)
      Interview. Beichman was a journalist. Interview with Beichman starts at 8 minutes.
    - Belica, Paul, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9464)
      Interview. Belica was the executive director of the New York State Housing Finance Agency.
    - Belin, David, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9465)
      Interview. Belin was an attorney for the Rockefeller Commission.
    - Bennett, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9466)
      Interview. Bennett was superintendent of the New York State Executive Mansion while Nelson Rockefeller was Governor. Interview ends at 84 minutes, 24 seconds. Remainder of tape is blank.
      Clicking starts around 48 minutes and continues for remainder of tape.
    - Berle, Peter, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette; Sound, 62 minutes (Tape AV 15675)
      Interview. Berle was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1969-1974. He was the son of Adolf Augustus Berle, Jr. and Dr. Beatrice Berle. As a freshman assemblyman, he successfully sued then Governor Nelson Rockefeller over budgetary process issues.
    - Berger, Stephen - Part 1, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9467)
      Interview. Berger was executive director of the Scott Commission, 1972-1973, and a consultant to the Rockefeller Commission on Critical Choices for Americans, 1973-1974. He was also executive director of the New York Emergency Control Board for the City of New York. Berger interview ends at 47 minutes. Tape then contains interivew with Arthur Richardson until end. Richardson was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Berger, Stephen - Part 2, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9703)
      Interview. Berger was executive director of the Scott Commission, 1972-1973, and a consultant to the Rockefeller Commission on Critical Choices for Americans, 1973-1974. He was also executive director of the New York Emergency Control Board for the City of New York.
    - Bigel, Jack, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9468)
      Interview. Bigel was a labor union consultant and negotiator.
    - Bixby, Burdell, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9469)
      Interview. Bixby was chairman of the New York State Thruway Authority, 1960-1970, and managed Governor Nelson Rockefeller's re-election campaign in 1970. Bixby interview ends at 31 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape continues with interview with Dorothy Miller. Miller was a curator at the Museum of Modern Art and a consulatant and curator for numerous art projects for the Rockefeller family. Miller interview ends at 63 minutes. Tape continues with interview with Bixby. Bixby interview ends at 105 minutes, 20 seconds. Tape continues with interview with William Alton. Alton was a friend and IBEC aide. Alton interview ends at 107 minutes, 37 seconds. Tape continues with interviews with multiple unidentified individuals until 157 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape continues with interview with Bixby until end.
    - Bolton, Lee, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9471)
      Interview with art photographer Lee Bolton. Collaborated with Nelson Rockefeller in the 1970s on art book projects.
    - Bowker, Albert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9472)
      Interview. Bowker was chancellor of the City University of New York and then the University of California, Berkeley. Bowker interview ends at 65 minutes, 52 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Charles Webb until end. Webb was counsel to New York State Assemblyman Perry Duryea and worked on the reapportionment of legislature districts.
    - Boyd, Joe, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9473)
      Interview with Joseph Boyd, Governor Nelson Rockefeller's Congressional liaison officer in Washington, DC. Boyd also served as the Governor's liaison to the New York State legislature.
    - Boyer, Ernest, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9474)
      Interview. Boyer was chancellor of the State University of New York system.
    - Braden, Joan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9475)
      Interview. Braden was a friend of Nelson Rockefeller and a Rockefeller family aide. Braden interview ends at 132 minutes, 54 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with George Shapiro until end. Shapiro was counsel to New York Governor Thomas Dewey.
    - Braden, Tom, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9476)
      Interview. Braden was a friend and family aide. Braden interview ends at 118 minutes, 44 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Rodman Rockefeller until end. Rodman Rockefeller was the son of Nelson Rockefeller. He was vice president of the International Basic Economy Corporation, 1968 to 1972, and its chief executive, 1972 to 1980.
    - Brinton, William, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9477)
      Interview. Brinton was national chairman for the Draft Rockefeller movement. Tape begins with partial interview with Josh Friedman. Friedman was a reporter for the New York Post. Brinton interview begins at 5 minutes, 18 seconds and ends at 27 minutes, 48 seconds. Tape continues with interview with Friedman until end.
    - Bronston, Jack, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9478)
      Interview. Bronston was a New York State senator.
    - Brown, Richard A., circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9479)
      Interview. Richard A. Brown was the legislative representative for New York City, 1970-1973. Brown interview ends at 87 minutes, 22 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with William Golub until end. Golub was an attorney who was special assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller for rail and commuter problems. He was also special consultant to the Moreland Act Commission to draft legislation that created sweeping changes in New York State's liquor laws.
    - Brownell, Herbert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9480)
      Interview. Brownell was the U.S. Attorney General during the first Eisenhower administration.
    - Bruno, Joseph, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9481)
      Interview. Bruno was a campaign aide.
    - Buckley, Jr., William F., circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9482)
      Interview. Buckley was the founder of National Review magazine. Interview starts at 5 minutes and ends at 21 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with Evelyn Cunningham until end. Cunningham was a reporter for the Pittsburgh Courier in its Harlem office and then special assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. She was appointed director of the Women's Unit within the Governor's Office.
    - Burbank, Kershaw, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9483)
      Interview. Burbank was a campaign and family aide.
    - Burns, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9484)
      Interview. Burns was Mayor of Binghamton, New York, in the 1950s and early 1960s, who then served as New York State Democratic chair during the 1960s.
    - Button, Daniel, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9485)
      Interview. Button was assistant to the president of the State University of New York, 1952-1958; executive editor of the Albany Times Union newspaper, 1960-1966; and a Republican member of the United States House of Representatvies, 1967-1971.
    - Byron, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9486)
      Interview. Byron was director of construction of the South Mall for the State Office of General Services, an agency Governor Nelson Rockefeller created to oversee the project.
  - C-D, 2.2
    - Cain, Edward, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9487)
      Interview. Cain was chairman of the Genesee County Republican Committee.
    - Callan, Albert and Virginia, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9488)
      Interview. Albert Callan was a Columbia County (New York) Republican leader, and Virginia Callan was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Callaway, Bo, circa1980s; Sound, 35 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9489)
      Interview. Callaway was chairman of the President Ford Committee, June 1975-March 1976. Callaway interview ends at 22 minutes, 29 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Warren Weaver until end. Weaver was a reporter for the New York Times.
      Pitch is too high, speed is too fast, and audio crackles for first 22 minutes, 29 seconds, making the interview unintelligible in parts.
    - Camp, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9490)
      Interview. Camp was an AIA-IBEC aide.
    - Campbell, Donald, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9491)
      Interview. Campbell was a Republican New York State Assemblyman, 1951-1968. He was also Republican Party chairman of Montgomery County.
    - Cannon, Jim, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9492)
      Interview. Cannon was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller when he was Governor of New York and then Vice President.
    - Canzeri, Joseph, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9493)
      Interview. Canzeri was an advance man for Governor Nelson Rockefeller, and later president of Greenrock Corporation.
    - Carberry, Jim, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9494)
      Interview. Carberry was a speech writer for Nelson Rockefeller and John Lindsay.
    - Carey, Hugh, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9495)
      Interview. Carey was a Democratic Governor of New York who beat Republican Malcolm Wilson (who served out Nelson Rockefeller's fourth term). Previously had served several terms in the U.S. House of Representatives.
    - Carlino, Joseph, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9496)
      Interview. Carlino was the New York State Assembly Majority Leader.
    - Case, Gene, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9497)
      Interview. Case was an advertising executive who developed ads for Nelson Rockefeller's successful bid for a third term as governor in 1966.
    - Chilcote, Lee, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9498)
      Interview. Chilcote was a Dartmouth classmate.
    - Clendinen, Dudley, 1982 April 2; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15676)
      Interview. Clendinen was a national correspondent and editorial writer for the New York Times, during which he wrote at least one story about Nelson Rockefeller. Tape also contains an interview with Clendinen's wife.
    - Compilation: Barber Conable, John Sears, Oscar Lanford, John Egan, Charles Lanigan, Lois Wilson, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9586)
      Interview. Conable was a New York State senator and then a member of the U.S. House of Representatives. Conable interview ends at 47 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Sears until 72 minutes, 43 seconds. Sears was Ronald Reagan's campaign manager during the 1976 Republican presidential primaries. Tape then contains partial interview with Lanford until 94 minutes, 24 seconds. Lanford was the president of the SUNY Fredonia. Tape then contains partial interview with Egan until 150 minutes, 14 seconds. Egan was commissioner of the Office of General Services. Tape then contains partial interview with Lanigan until 188 minutes, 30 seconds. Lanigan was mayor of Rome, New York, 1959-1962, and later was on Governor Nelson Rockefeller's staff for six connsecutive years in various capacities. Tape then contains partial interview with Wilson until 233 minutes, 32 seconds. Wilson was a gubernatorial aide to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Conable, Barber, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9499)
      Interview. Conable was a Republican New York State senator and then a member of the U.S. House of Representatives. Conable interview ends at 51 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Oscar Ruebhausen until end. Ruebhausen was a friend and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. Under Governor Rockefeller, Ruebhausen served in a number of capacities, including as chairman of the Special Task Force on Protection from Radioactive Fallout, as Special Adviser on Atomic Energy, and as chairman of a panel on insurance holding companies.
    - Conboy, Brian, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9500)
      Interview. Conboy was campaign manager for U.S. Senator Charles Goodell, Republican from New York.
    - Conway, Edward, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15682)
      Interview. Conway was a New York State Supreme Court Justice and Republican Party chairman of Albany County. Conway interview ends at 42 minutes, 22 seconds. Tape the contains partial interview with David Rockefeller until end. David Rockefeller was Nelson Rockefeller's brother.
    - Coral, Joy, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9501)
      Interview. Coral was a Republican worker.
    - Corbett, Raymond, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9502)
      Interview. Corbett was the legislative director of the New York State A.F.L-C.I.O.
    - Corbin, Sol Neil, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9503)
      Interview. Successively, Corbin was Assistant Counsel to the Governor; Counsel to the Governor; Assistant to the Governor in the Attica riot investigation; and Special Counsel to the Vice President for the Commission on CIA Activities.
    - Corning, Elizabeth, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9504)
      Interview. Corning was the wife of Erastus Corning, who was the mayor of Albany.
    - Edward N. Costikyan, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9505)
      Interview. Chair of New York County Democratic Committee in 1960s; appointed by Nelson Rockefeller to commission that investigated New York City government in 1970s.
    - Crangle, Joseph, and Rangel, Charles, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9699)
      Interview. Crangle was Erie County (NY) Democratic chair and then New York State Democratic chair. Crangle interview ends at 93 minutes, 24 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Charles Rangel until end. Rangel was a Democratic New York State Assembly member from 1967 to 1970 and a member of the U.S. House of Representatives for district including Harlem from 1971 to 2017. Governor Nelson Rockefeller endorsed Rangel for his 1968 reelection to the New York State Assembly.
    - Crown, Alfred, 1982 September 16; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15681)
      Interview. Crown was a film producer who worked in the motion picture divison of the State Department in Latin America during World War 2 showing United States propaganda films to local heads of companies. Outside of that, Crown was president of Moulin Productions and later vice president of international sales for Samuel Goldwyn Productions and R.K.O. Pictures, and he worked for Allied Artists and Aladan Productions. At the time of his death, he was senior vice president in charge of Penthouse Films International Ltd.
    - Cunningham, Evelyn, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9506)
      Interview. Cunningham was a reporter for the Pittsburgh Courier in its Harlem office and special assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller. She was appointed director of the Women's Unit within the Governor's Office.
    - Cuomo, Mario, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9507)
      Interview. Cuomo was Secretary of State of New York, 1975-1978, Lieutenant Governor of New York, 1979-1982, and then Governor of New York, 1983-1994. Cuomo interview ends at 68 minutes, 35 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Curcio, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9508)
      Interview. Curcio was Suffolk County (NY) Republican chair.
    - Curran, Paul, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9509)
      Interview. Curran was a member of the New York State Assembly and chair of the New York State Commission of Investigation.
    - Curto, Ernest, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9510)
      Interview. Curto was a Niagara County Republican representative in the New York State Assembly.
    - Danzig, Jerry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9511)
      Interview. Danzig was Special Assistant to Governor Nelson Rockefeller for Radio and Television. Danzig interview ends at 71 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with T. Norman Hurd until end. Hurd was Director of State Operations.
    - Deardourff, John, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9512)
      Interview. Deardourff was a campaign aide.
    - Diamond, Henry, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9514)
      Interview. Diamond was an environmental lawyer and New York first Commissioner of Environmental Conservation. He other roles included Laurance Rockefeller associate; Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commissioner; 1960 and 1968 NAR Presidential campaign advisor; Adirondacks Park Commissioner. Diamond interivew ends at 55 minutes, 23 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Gillies. Gillies was an IBEC aide. Gillies interview ends at 91 minutes, 23 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individal until 94 minutes. Tape then continues with interview with Diamond until end.
    - DiCarlo, Dominick, circa 1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15677)
      Interview. DiCarlo was a Republican New York State Assemblyman, 1965-1981. He was the only Republican in the State Assembly who voted against the Rockfeller drug laws.
    - Dietel, Bill, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9515)
      Interview. Dietel was executive vice president and president of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund.
    - Dilworth, J. Richardson, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9516)
      Interview. Richardson was a lawyer and financial adviser to the Rockefeller family and manager of Room 5600.
    - Dominick, III, D. Clinton, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9517)
      Interview. Dominick was a member of the New York State Assembly and then a New York State senator from Newburgh.
    - Douglass, Robert, circa1980s; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9519)